Heat. Heat. N.
[music]
Yeah.
Heat.
>> [music]
[music]
>> Don't be
down. [music]
>> [music]
>> The Lions were hoping for some gifts in
their stockings today during a Christmas
Day matchup with the Vikings. Well, they
got cold. Detroit's playoff hopes have
been squashed with a 23-10 loss in week
17. Welcome to the Detroit Lions live
postgame show presented by Curado
Insurance alongside the Super Bowl
champion Lomus Brown. I'm Danny Rogers.
Detroit came into today with the fewest
turnovers in the NFL, just eight. Today
alone, they tacked on six turnovers.
Jared Goff had five of those. And
despite being down six going into the
fourth quarter, the Lions could not
complete the comeback win today. Yeah,
Danny, it was starting to look a little
bit like last week where they set
themselves up with a chance to come back
towards the end, but Danny, I don't care
what team you are, when you have that
amount of turnovers in the game, it's
just so hard to win the game. And it
reared his ugly head against us. Uh, I
mean, Minnesota, yeah, you give them
credit cuz they forced a lot of those
turnovers, but it was just an
uncharacteristic type of game from the
Detroit Lions, especially from the
offense. offense gave up five sacks.
Meanwhile, the defense tacked on seven
sacks of their own. They gave this team
a chance to win, especially keeping
quarterback Max Bromer to just three net
yards passing. They still got it done
when they needed it the most. Head coach
Dan Campbell is standing by the podium.
Let's hear from him.
>> All right, story of that game was six
turnovers.
Uh can't turn the ball over six times
and and win in in this league. Um,
you know, defense did some really good
things. Um, you know,
that getting stop after stop. Um, you
know, offensively, I thought we played
hard. We just could not, you know, you
turn the ball over that many times, it's
uh, it's going to hurt. So, that's what
got us.
>> You you guys knew it was hard. Is that
disappointing the performance? Uh, I
mean, you know, losing is is very
disappointing. Losing. I hate losing.
They hate losing. We do. But it it look
I mean some of these things that come up
it's I mean the effort's there. It's
just boy we are not uh you know we're
just a little off here and it's and it's
costing us significantly you know and uh
we just you know there again too many
turnovers that that's what really got us
man. just couldn't overcome it.
>> We've lost a lot of players and always
been able to uh you know, next man up,
bounce bounce back, find ways to win.
And uh you know, we felt good about Skip
going in there and battling and uh you
know, and I haven't watched the tape. I
know that here's what I know out of
Skip. He's going to give us everything
he's got and he's going to battle and
he's going to finish and uh so,
you know, I trust Skip.
>> How do you how do you explain big
picture?
>> Yeah, but we turned the ball over six
times today. That's the first one. Um
and then last week, uh we we just
couldn't, you know, we couldn't score in
the red zone late when we needed it.
once their pass rush was able to start
getting home. How did that kind of
change the dynamic of what golf was?
>> Well, you know, anytime you he's not
able to step into throw, it's going to
be hard for him. You know, that's where
he's at his best obviously in the
pocket. And you know, if he's not able
to uh to at least hit that back foot and
step into it, it makes it pretty
difficult, you know, and uh you know,
that that defense puts a lot on you, you
know, and it was a short week and they
they uh they, you know, really they did
a lot, you know, they went all out and,
you know, uh it's really that type of
game where a you have to be able to run
the ball, you need to pop a run, you
can't turn the ball over, and then you
just need two shots. It really is that
type of game where, you know, you come
away doing that and the the stats may be
ugly, but you come away with the two
shot plays that made the difference, the
two touchdowns, and we just couldn't,
you know, we couldn't get those. So,
>> it was six turnovers today, but the
truth is you guys haven't played that
well for a few weeks now. And you know,
is there something larger picture you
need to look at? I know the season isn't
over, but the playoffs are over. Is
there something you bigger picture you
need to start looking at?
>> Yeah, I'm going to be looking at a lot,
you know. Um I'm going be looking at a
lot of things. Um
because I do not like being home for the
playoffs and um I know our guys don't
either. So, you know, and there again,
whenever you lose, man, it it's uh takes
a village, man. Everybody's involved,
including myself, you know. So, um, I'm
always going to look at myself first,
you know. I'm always going to wish I
would have given golf more, given those
players more, you know, like on a day
like today, you come out, you lose, win,
doesn't matter, man. You know, you feel
like you you need to improve or can't
improve, you want to. So,
>> on the first, you know, fumble center
quarterback exchange, you just snap that
too early on that play, what to start?
>> Yeah. Well, Graham, man, uh Graham was
good enough to help us as a reserve.
He's got that knee and uh so we were
fortunate to even have him as a reserve.
Um and so gave Kingsley another go. Um
so, and yeah, just it it just got
snapped early.
>> And you talked about finding your guys
identity. It
>> clearly isn't going to be rebound this
season, I don't think. How difficult
will be that be to rebind it?
>> Well, we got one game to go, man. And um
you know, I expect everybody to to be
ready to go when we get back in in a
couple of days. Uh be locked in and uh
be ready when we get on the plane to go
to Chicago. Um you know, to be locked in
one more time. That's what I expect. And
uh and then we'll go from there. You
know, Brad, Brad and I have a lot of
decisions to make. you know, a lot of
things to look at the what'ss, the wise,
the how do we improve because we need to
improve.
Um,
>> yeah.
>> Well, you know, until I have time to
really sit down and soak everything up.
Uh, I don't know if I can quite answer
that. I know this, it doesn't take much
for for things to get off balance, you
know. It it really
um not as much as you would think, you
know. So, sometimes it can be it can be
one thing here. Um it could be one
player, it could be one coach, it could
be um
you know,
you just you just never know. Or the
placement of of somebody. Yeah. maybe he
needs to be playing here or maybe he
needs to be doing this or and uh you
know every team's different every year
man and even if you have the core which
you believe in why we've got them is
that man it's a new it's always a new
team you got to find your your own way
man um so it's disappointing you know
it's disappointing so
but it is what it is
>> you
Guys, your prior success has put you at
the top of the power rankings list.
That's a good thing, right?
>> Well, just means you've gone from the
underdog to the favorite.
>> But those expectations come from prior
success, so that's okay.
>> What about Cure? Where do you guys rank
on the power list?
>> Actually, we just got named by Forbes as
one of the best car insurance companies
in America.
>> Now, you're the favorite.
>> Guess we have a lot in common.
>> Go Cure. [music]
>> Go Lions.
Cure Auto Insurance. Drive well.
>> Detroit Lions Live is brought to you by
Cure Auto Insurance. Log on to cure.com
to see how you can save.
Detroit Lions wide receiver Aman Ross
St. Brown continues to be a mainstay and
a consistent guy for Detroit. He
captured his one 100th reception here
today. Second catch coming in the second
quarter. four years in a row he's now
hit that 100 reception mark. That is a
franchise record. Lis, what did you see
out of him as he tried to, you know, get
this offense back in the swing of things
throughout the game?
>> More of the same, Danny. I mean, he's a
constant force that we can always depend
on. He's again someone that Jared has
ultimate trust in. He's a guy you know
what you're going to get out of him day
in and day out. Practice in, practice
out, game in, game out. He's just a
consmate pro. I don't expect anything
less than that from Arman Ro and he
doesn't expect anything less from
himself. So, it's just great that we
have a talent like him on this team and
without a doubt he's one of our
unquestioned leaders on this team.
>> Unquestionably the most impressive drive
Detroit had today was in the second
quarter. 19play drive ended in the end
zone. Isaac Tesla just copy and paste
all of his catches. They're usually
acrobatic for one and number two,
they're usually in the end zone for a
touchdown.
>> You're right. I mean, it's unbelievable
what he's done this year. And not just
Danny, the only regret I have is that
they just couldn't find ways to utilize
him more throughout this season. But
you're right, he is a ultimate weapon.
He's a guy that you could go up to. He's
a guy that you can trust. If he has an
opportunity to make that catch, he's
going to make it. And like you say,
normally it's in the end zone resulting
in seven play seven points. So I mean
again, I'm looking forward to what he's
going to bring to this offense for years
and years to come.
>> I mean that was a hard fall, but there
was no doubt Tesla was going to go up
and come down with that football.
>> Yeah, I mean almost copy and paste from
what happened last week. He just
couldn't climb the ladder as much
against Pittsburgh, but he was able to
get up there tonight, bring it down, and
yes, that's a that's called sacrificing
your body, doing whatever you can to
help this team win. And he's one of
those guys that has bought in. And he's
committing that body to do whatever he
can to help us.
>> He's turning into a favorite target for
quarterback Jared Goff, who was sacked
seven times tonight. when he was in the
pocket and he had time, he was really
efficient. But that was far and few in
between today.
>> Lis, it really was. But Danny, we knew
that. We expected that. We know when we
face a Brian Flores type of defense,
he's going to bring it. He's going to
bring pressure through the A gaps. He's
going to bring guys off the edges. So,
we should have expected that. I think
Jared had some of his hot reads. A
couple of times he just didn't have
enough time to get that ball out to the
guys that he wanted to. Um, you got to
give Minnesota a lot of credit. That's
their MMO. That's they stuck to it and
they had success.
>> Defensively, that unit gave Detroit a
chance to win, coming up with seven
sacks and holding Max Bromer to just
three net yards passing. Defensive end
Aiden Hutchinson. He eclipsed his
careerhigh with 13 and a half sacks here
tonight. Two rather tonight. 13 and a
half on the season. and he was resilient
and he lit up the stat sheet tonight,
>> Lomus.
>> Yes, he did. I mean, and that's what we
expect from Aiden Hutcherson. He is a
relentless rusher. He's a guy that's
going to get after that quarterback.
He's a tone setter for us on the
defensive side of the ball. He just
needs more help, Danny. I mean, that's
what I think Brad Holmes, the coaching
staff, have to look at. How do we get
more help out there with Aiden
Hutcherson to really just unleash what
he can do? Normally he's doubled triple
team, but again, you know what you're
going to get from Aiden. You're going to
get a allout effort from Aiden
Hutcherson. And I'm happy for him that
he was able to set his career high
tonight in sacks.
>> Mhm. Another bookend for Detroit's
defense, and I don't know if we would
have seen him getting 10 sacks on the
season, but it's Elquad Mohamd. The most
sacks he's ever had in one season was
six. He blew that careerhigh out of the
water. He's he's turning into someone
that this off this staff rather has to
take a look at in the off season and
make a decision on whether or not he's a
line in the future.
>> Danny, the only thing he needs to do is
become more consistent. That's it. I
mean, again, he has all the tools in the
bag. He's a relentless rusher. He showed
that. But his thing is that he has to
just show more consistency and be able
to show the coaching staff that they can
trust him out there to be the guy that
he needs to be opposite of Aiden
Hutcherson. So again, the future looks
bright with him out there. I'm happy he
got his opportunity. And what you say
when you get an opportunity, you just
have to take advantage of it. And Cordin
Muhammad, he took advantage of it. Yeah,
a few more Lions did in the sack party
as well today. But linebacker Jack
Campbell every single week. Dan Campbell
goes on about the core of his linebacker
crew, the core of this defense really.
He's over 160 tackles on this season.
And he's a Pro Bowler for the first time
in his career, too.
>> Impressive. Impressive. He's been that
way from game one, from practice one.
Jack has been the man on defensive side
of the ball. kind of reminds me of my
old former teammate Chris Spielman with
how these guys are just ball players.
They just see ball, get ball, and that's
what Jack Campbell does. He's been a
model of consistency himself on the
defensive side of the ball, taking on
more responsibility, becoming the signal
caller for our defense. So, I expect
Jack to just continue to grow, continue
to grow into that role of being the
defensive leader on that side of the
ball. getting guys in position to have
success and being the tackling machine
that he has become.
>> Time of possession went in the Lions
favor. Third over 32 minutes to
Minnesota's 27 and a half. So they're
winning the time of possession battle. I
know the biggest Achilles heel today was
self-inflicted wounds with the
turnovers,
>> but it did feel like Detroit was in in
this game the entire time despite that
>> we were. Think about that. Like I say,
it was almost kind of a carbon copy to
what happened last week where we gave
oursel a opportunity to pull that game
out in the end. And you're right. Now,
Brazmer, he's not very good. And he was
part of the reasons why we stayed in the
game. But you're right, man. When you
turn the ball over six times, it's hard
to beat a high school team that way, let
alone a pro team. So, I mean, again,
that's was those are lessons learned. We
know that. We knew that coming into the
game. So, you know, it's something that
we have to just deal with, Danny. And
hopefully we correct this because we
have we still got another game in the
season to go and this against our
vaulted rivals in Chicago. So, hey, I
expect these guys to get geared up and
want to play spoiler to the Chicago
Bears.
>> Another important part of the defense
today making Max Bromer so uncomfortable
was Alexandone. He made his presence
felt early with the sack. aided in
pressuring the quarterback and making
sure he was onedimensional whether or
not Bromer wanted to be two-dimensional
or not.
>> Yeah, you were right about that. And
again, that's what you love to do. You
would love to make these guys
one-dimensional. I think we did a great
job of doing that. And again, Danny,
these are things that we can take and we
can learn from. These are things we'll
take into next season and everything.
And I think this team will become better
for this. It's hard to say that right
now when you come off a loss like this,
but these are things that you put in
your memory bank. You store back there
and then like I say, you just continue
to get better from there.
>> Well, I'm going to store it in there and
actually never think about it again. QB1
Jared Goff is standing by at the podium.
Let's hear from him.
>> Um we've been really good at all year
and it sucks that it reared its head
today and um yeah, really bad by us in
that area. When you have done this
season, did you ever envision the
possibility that you guys could miss?
>> No.
>> What are the emotions about that?
>> About what?
>> Yeah, it sucks. It sucks. Um,
we we'll reflect on the whole season
after next week, but yeah, it sucks.
on the first one there.
>> Yeah, it's a little miscommunication
between him and I
>> when they're getting home like they
were. How does that kind of change the
dynamic of what you're looking at the
line? Does it speed it up at all?
>> Yeah, it can. Um they did a good job on
defense. had a good plan and exploited
some things on us and um yeah were able
to get after us uh adding adding an
extra rusher a lot of times and um
whenever that happens you know it's a
free rusher I'm hot and uh they did a
good job with that we we had a plan that
um we thought would attack that and it
didn't work well enough you have a 19
play 80 yard touchdown drive before the
half I mean you show what this offense
is capable of and then the second half
just how frustrating is that when you
see literally what you're able to do
>> yeah you know we had some good plays on
that. We had some good third down
conversions and um you know they they
they came out in the second half and
adjusted pretty well and had some
different stuff for us and we didn't do
well a good enough job on our side of of
uh adjusting to those different things
they were doing.
>> What do you think this team has had the
performances outside the last two weeks
with the season number one?
>> Um I don't know. They're different
games. I don't I wouldn't I wouldn't
group them together. Different different
games and um got beaten different ways.
Have you been under siege as much as you
were today on the pass rush at all this
year? Is that the most
>> I don't know. I maybe I'm not sure. I
can't think of any right now, but they
did a good job.
All good.
>> Thank you,
>> guys. Your prior success has put you at
the top of the power rankings list.
That's a good thing, right?
>> Well, just means you've gone from the
underdog to the favorite. But those
expectations come from prior success, so
that's okay.
>> What about Cure? Where do you guys rank
on the power list?
>> Actually, we just got named by Forbes as
one of the best car insurance companies
in America. [music]
>> Now you're the favorite.
>> Guess we have a lot in common.
>> Go Cure.
>> Go Lions.
>> Cure Auto Insurance. Drive well.
>> Detroit Lions Live is brought to you by
Cure Auto Insurance. Log on to cure.com
to see how you can save.
Up next in week 18 for the Detroit
Lions, this team is not playing for a
playoff seating. They are playing to
keep their record above 500 and try to
get a win over the Chicago Bears, a team
they haven't seen since week two and
hung 52 points on. But these two teams
are very different here at the end of
the season. Lom miss,
>> they really are. I mean, Chicago has
everything ahead in them. Then they will
play a little spoiler. Let's just try to
play spoiler like you say. We were able
to beat those guys pretty handily um in
week two. Now we get an opportunity to
finish the season with them and you
always want to finish the season on a
high especially going into this type of
all season. So hopefully we'll be able
to go to Chicago and have a much better
performance than we did today.
>> Game time still TBD in the Windy City.
As for final thoughts with these Detroit
Lions, after being reigning NFC
back-toback champions, Detroit will miss
the playoffs for the first time in three
seasons. Where do they go from here,
Lis?
>> I mean, Danny, it's really disappointing
how the season has ended up for us. Like
you say, after dominating this division
the last couple of years, now to be
looking from the bottom looking up. I
just think one thing is we have to get
healthy. We just definitely have to get
healthy. And I think you have to
re-evaluate some of the positions on
this team like your offensive line. Do
you have players that you can bring up
and guys that can be contributors next
year? You look at the secondary, what's
the status with Kirby Joseph and Brian
Branch next year. Um, again, I think we
have all the foundational pieces here to
be a good team and to recapture this
division, but it is some fundamental
things that we have to look at, try to
shore up even in the coaching staff. You
know, it's just some things that coach
Campbell, Brad Johnson, Brad Holmes, and
the rest of this staff are going to have
to look at during the offseason.
>> There's got to be some tough
conversations incoming for both the
players and the staff. All right, from
Minnesota, the final 23-10. Detroit
loses a Christmas Day matchup here in
week 17 and fall to 8 and 8 on this
season. That wraps it up for Lomus
Brown. I'm Danny Rogers. We'll see you
next week, week 18 in Chicago.
>> [music]
[music]
>> down. You know,